NITIN KUMAR

12561 112A Avenue Surrey, V3V 3L3, BC · +1 778 636 7121 kumarnitin.0798@gmail.com· https://nitink167.github.io/

OBJECTIVE

I am applying for Web Developer position in your company. I have more than 4 years of working experience with web development libraries. I would even like to work here full time if offered in future and would be more than willing to expand my duties and responsibilities.

Please have a look at my portfolio website: https://nitink167.github.io/

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2017 – AUGUST 2017

INTERN WORDPRESS DEVELOPER, INSPIREN TECHNOLOGIES, PANCHKULA, INDIA

Worked on premium WordPress themes and build powerful ecommerce websites with Woo commerce.

JUNE 2020 - JULY 2020

INTERN FULL STACK DEVELOPER, BRICK VIEW STUDIOS, KOLKATA, INDIA

Worked on React JS and Node.js. Built online learning platform with subscription based access to content.

Deployed website to google firebase platform.

Managed database, backend and frontend of the project.

SEPTEMBER 2017 – CURRENT

FREELANCING

Worked on premium WordPress themes and page builders like WC Page Builder, Elementor etc.

OCTOBER 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021

TECHNICAL SALES SPECIALIST, TREHAN CONSULTING GROUP, VANCOUVER

Worked on Inventory Management, Staffing Solutions and IT Support.

EDUCATION

2017-2020

BACHELOR OF COMMERCE, KURUKSHETRA UNIVERSITY

Completed with 65%. Studied about Business Management, Computer Systems, Digital Marketing, IT Support, Business Statistics, and Accounting.

2021-2023

POST DEGREE DIPLOMA - BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, LANGARA COLLEGE

Based on study of Organizational Behavior and Management, Accounting for Managers, Project Management, and Canadian Marketing Strategies as well.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS & Bootstrap
- PHP & WordPress
- Mongo DB, Express, React JS and Node.js
- State Management Libraries like Redux
- Google Cloud Platform
- Github and Deploying experience

MY WORK SAMPLES IN IT FIELD

- Online Learning Platform
- Ecommerce with MERN
- Instagram Clone with Laravel

- Twitter Clone
- YouTube Clone